Richard Chiriboga

Flushing, NY 11355 1 (347) 326-4434

RichardChiriboga@gmail.com 💟

Linkedin.com/in/richardchiriboga in

Driven and collaborative Technical Manager with more than 20-years of experience in web development and management, across non-profit, boutique agency and global company environments. Expertise in leading website restructuring and development projects, corporate intranet builds, and content management plans through their complete life cycle – from ideation to launch. Known for being a trusted partner across multiple vendors, functions and disciplines, and having the ability to communicate complex information to both technical and non-technical users. Offers Hispanic marketing and social media expertise: Created award-winning website CorrienteLatina.com. Fluent in English, with intermediate Spanish fluency.

Skills

- Technical Management
- Web Development Management
- Project Execution

- Waterfall / Agile Methodologies
- Front-End Web Development
- Digital Media / Marketing

Experience

11/2016 - 12/2017

Senior Manager, Web Development / Avon Breast Cancer Crusade, New York, NY Managed all project cycles while bridging the gap between cross-functional internal and external

Managed all project cycles while bridging the gap between cross-functional internal and external stakeholders to deliver a seamless digital solution using waterfall and agile methodology.

- Managed brand IT relationships and strategy with internal and remote third-party vendors across various projects. This included project SOW's, resources, budgets and conflict resolution.
- Implemented and standardized web design/development workflow to ensure updates and new functionality were pushed seamlessly.
- Standardized the email signature throughout the entire company by creating an online form that allowed staff to create a standardized email signature and easily add it to our Gmail environment.
- Led I.T. crisis management which included SSL and payment gateway issues.
- Developed an online check-in system used throughout the 2015-2017 event seasons. The "Check-In Friday" system allowed volunteers and staff to manage and report on participants and crew during physical event weekends.

06/2011 - 11/2016

Manager, Web Technologies / Avon Products Inc., New York, NY

Reported directly to the Senior Manager, Global Web Architecture, Global IT. Main responsibilities included managing all web properties owned by the Corporate Communications department such as the "InsideAvon" global intranet and corporate website - AvonCompany.com.

- Addressed corporate Intranet (InsideAvon) issues by spearheading and leading the front-end development effort to create a custom CMS built on .NET MVC, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery and knockout.js. Equipped with movable dynamic widgets and a simple image manipulator, it enabled content owners to update their respective websites effortlessly. InsideAvon housed 25 market and functional intranets.
- Improved associates digital experience by utilizing the latest trends to create a holistic socially interactive digital workplace. This included being part of the steering committee that rolled out Microsoft Office 365 to over 30,000 associates to replace Lotus Notes.
- Helped plan all aspects of project development including scope, objectives, deliverables, tasks, budgets, resources, schedules, coordinating cross-functional teams, and managing dependencies.
- Successfully managed Web Portals using various Content Management Systems for global functions like Human Resources, Finance, Legal and Global Travel Security.

06/2007 - 07/2010

Senior Web Developer / THAT Agency, West Palm Beach, FL

Worked directly with the president and project manager on all aspects from concept to creation for client websites.

- Part of leadership team that helped steer overall company on what technologies should be used for our spectrum of clients.
- Distinguished ourselves from other web boutiques by creating a custom content management system built in house and custom to each of our clients.
- Wrote technical blogs that allowed some of my web development work to be featured on quite a few "Top 10" lists for HTML/CSS/jQuery.

Education

05/2015

Certified ScrumMaster / Scrum Alliance, New York, NY

1993-1996

Informational Systems / Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY

Activities

I have owned and managed my own website since 2005, which markets entertainment news, advanced movie screenings and events. We won a Tecla Award for "Best Latino News and Culture" website by Hispanicize / Telemundo. I am an avid music listener and movie buff. I also volunteer web development time to a few nonprofits including "Travel with Purpose", "Stop Bullying Tour" and "Hair We Care". I had the privilege of being honored by Jack Daniels as 2017 Jack Daniel's Neighborhood Flavors Honoree for the "Movers & Shakers" category for helping the Hispanic Community in Queens, NY.